09 /01/01
开始上幼儿园
12/11/02
第一次落齿
11/24/03
第一次本垒打
07/08/06
九岁生日
11/13/07
爸爸去世
- Dre, you're ready?
- Yeah, one second.
德瑞 你准备好了吗
嗯 等一下
Oh Dre, I am so excited!
It's like we are brave pioneers,
德瑞 我很兴奋
好像我们是即将踏上征途的勇敢先锋
on a quest to start a new life
in a magical, new land.
在一个神气的国土开始新的生活
You could say that.
你可以那样说
Okay, all right, let's go.
好吧 我们走
- And don't forget to use the bathroom.
- Okay.
别忘了上个厕所
好的
搬到中国
我知道 我知道 我知道
好的 好的
Be careful with that guys, okay?
我才刚做好头发
好 那个小心一点 好
再见 查理叔叔
- I'll see you later, uncle Charlie.
- C'mon Dre, we can't miss this plane!
快点 德瑞 我们不能误了飞机
Bye guys!
We're gonna miss you.
再见 我会想你们的
- No man, it's yours.
- C'mon Dre, just take it.
别这样 这是你的
得了 德瑞 拿着
Thanks, man!
谢了 兄弟
Okay Dre, c'mon, we have to go.
Okay, bye guys!
好啦 德瑞 快点 我们必须要走了
好 再见 我们一落地就打电话
We'll call you as soon as we land.
国航
- Ladies and gentlemen, welcome to flight CA982.
- You got it? - Yeah.
各位先生和女士
欢迎乘坐此班至北京的CA982
德瑞 看 我们已学到第十课了
- With our service to Beijing.
- Oh Dre look, we are already on lesson ten.
How are you?
你好吗
你叫什么名字
- Remember what that one is?
- No.
- 记得这句什么意思吗
- 不知道
Dre, you're killing me.
德瑞 别这样
Mom, look, in China everything is old.
There's old houses, old parks...
妈 你看 中国的一切都很老
老房子 老公园 老人
old people...Look, this guy is at least
four-hundred years old.
看 这位起码四百岁了
Dre, please focus.
Okay?
德瑞 认真点好不好
你叫什么名字
What's your name?
You need to practice.
Yeah, you need to try.
你需要练习 对 你试试
No, mom.
- 妈 我不要
- 试试看 德瑞
- Yes, Dre. Dre...
- Mom?
- Ask him. Go ahead.
- No, mom.
问他 去啊
问他“你叫什么名字”和“你好吗” 现在就去
Ask him "what's your name"
and "how are you". Do it, now.
你好吗 你叫什么名字
Dude, I'm from Detroit.
小兄弟 我从底特律来的
What's up?
哦 你好
此次航班飞行时间为十三个半小时
我们会先为您提供晚餐
希望您享受国航为您提供的愉快旅程
It's said to meet her
at number five.
他们说在第五号站台
Mrs. Packer?
派克太太
- 你好
- Hi. It's Parker.
- Oh, apologies, Mrs. Parker. Welcome to Beijing.
是帕克
不好意思 帕克太太 欢迎来到北京
好 帕克太太 这是租约
Look! There is Omatek village.
Isn't it beautiful?
看 奥运村多美啊
Yes. I guess there's nothing
old in China, huh Dre?
德瑞 中国没有那么老吧
Look at that, Dre. Beverly Hills.
看 德瑞 比华利山庄
We've always talked about
living there, huh?
以前不是总说想住在那里吗
I think we have talked
about the other one, mom.
妈 我们说的是另一个“比华利山庄”吧
I got a good feeling about this.
我对这儿有很好的预感
Oh, yeah. You must be the new
dude in 305. I'm Harry.
对 你一定是305新来的家伙 我叫哈里
- Hey, what's up? I'm Dre.
- Here. Let me help you.
你好 我叫德瑞
- 来 我帮你
- 谢啦
Thanks, man.
- Welcome to the building, Dre.
- Thanks.
- 欢迎你
- 德瑞 谢谢
Can you please explain this electricity card,
because we-we don't have these in America.
可以再解释一下这张电卡吗
我们在美国没用过
- 李师傅你好
- 你好
- Know any Chinese?
- Nah.
你会中文吗
不会
This is China.
Might not be a bad idea.
这里是中国 你应该要学学
Oh, that's our park.
You should come.
那里是我们的公园你一起来吧
Look at you.
Making friends already.
看看你 已经交新朋友了
- Hi, I'm Dre's mother.
- Nice to meet you.
你好 我是德瑞的妈妈
Nice to meet you too.
You can call me Miss Sherry.
- 很高兴认识您
- 我也很高兴认识你
- 你可以叫我雪莉小姐
- 我叫哈里
- I'm Harry.
- Hi, Harry.
你好 哈里
- So, I guess, I'll see you later, then?
- Maybe.
那我们等一下见喽
Okay, cool. See you.
- 可能吧
- 好待会儿见
Ok, this is your rental agreement in English.
这是你的合约
So the landlady is Mrs. Wong.
Her English is not good.
房东王太太的英文不太好
But if something goes wrong,
you go to Mr. Han.
如果有问题可以去找韩先生
他的英文不错
- His English is very good.
- Okay.
Okay. So, welcome to Beijing, Mrs. Parker.
Um, so I see you tomorrow, okay?
- 好的
- 好
北京欢迎您 帕克太太
- 那么明天见
- 好的 一定
Okay, sure! Thank you.
Oh, wait, wait!
等 等一下
Um, you mentioned something
about going...
之前你提过关于去公安局
Oh, this is perfect, Dre. Everything we
need is in walking distance.
太好了 一切都很棒 德瑞
我们需要去的地方走着都能到
Oh, you know what,
we can have lunch together
你知道吗
我们可以每天在你的学校一起吃午饭
every day at your school,
if you wanted to.
Negative! Not a chance.
我才不要呢
Dre, we are not doing this in Beijing.
德瑞 在北京不许再这样了
Dre, pick up your jacket!
德瑞 把外套捡起来
Mom, I'm tired, okay?
I have airplane lag.
妈 我很累 我有飞差
Airplane...
“飞差”
It's jet lag.
是时差
I know baby, I got it too.
我知道 宝贝 我也是
But, we can't go to sleep. Cause then we'll
be up at 2 A.M. You have school tomorrow.
但是我们不能睡
不然就会睡到半夜两点起来
你明天还要上学
Dre, can you please go
find the maintenance man?!
德瑞 去找一下维修员
I need to take a shower,
and the hot water is broken!
- 我要洗澡 可是热水坏了
- 好
Yes.
Excuse me.
请问
Um, the maintenance man?
Mr. Han?
我想找维修员
韩先生
老韩啊 出门往左走 再往左走
Thanks.
谢谢
Mr. Han?
韩先生
Me and my mom, we just moved in. 305.
The hot water is not working.
我和我妈妈刚搬进305
现在没有热水
Mr. Han?
韩先生
Okay. Alright I just come back another time.
好吧
我可以之后再过来
Or you can just show me how to do it so,
I can get out of your hair.
或者你可以告诉我该怎么做 我就走
Um, I can always come back
if this is bad time.
嗯 现在不方便 我换个时间再来找你
韩先生
怎么回事 这个马桶套件怎么老出问题啊
这可不成啊 你快走走走赶紧给我看看去
老出问题 不是这 刚开始是这个
- Hey man, you made it. Welcome.
- Thanks.
- 兄弟你来了
- 欢迎 谢谢
- You play, right? C'mon.
- Yeah.
- 你玩吗
- 好
来吧
你好 我们三个一起 打你们四个一队
- Us three against them four.
- All right.
咱们三个对他们四个
好
去那边
不错 不错
Pass!
传球
What's up?
怎么了 怎么了
My shooting hand.
Got some jet lag so...
我投球的手好像也有点时差
You know, I'm just...
我还是
You want this?
要这个
You want me to play? You know
I have no problem beatin' old people.
你要我玩
赢老人我可没什么问题
Back where I come from they call me
"Ping Pong Dre", alright?
在家乡他们可是叫我乒乓德瑞的
I'm going to take it easy on you.
我会让着你点的
Come on, man.
I'm twelve.
嘿 不用较真吧 我才12岁
He is really good.
I've never seen him lose to anybody.
他超强 从未输过呢
Yeah.
没错
- Dude. You're gonna talk to her or what?
- To who?
这家伙
- 你到底要不要去跟她说话
- 跟谁
- To her. The girl you've been staring at.
- I wasn't staring at her, dude.
她 你一直盯着的那个女孩儿
我没盯着她
Yeah, you were.
你明明就有
- You should go talk to her, unless you're scared?
- I'm not scared of any girl.
去跟她讲话 除非你害怕
我什么女孩都不怕
Then do it. Go.
Come on.
那去啊 去
Right now.
好 马上就去
Hey, what's up?
你好
你在干嘛
I forgot.
No English, um...
我忘了 不讲英文
你好吗
What language was that?
你在说哪国语言
You speak English?
Me too.
你会讲英文 我也是
- So, what are you listening to?
- Bach.
那 你在听什么
巴赫
Bach, I listen to them all the time.
They are tight. Have you ever heard of this?
巴赫 我常常听他们 他们不错
等一下 你有没有听过这个
Oh yeah, you like it huh, right?!
喜欢吧 不错吧
Great move, one over here.
看 节奏到了这里
- Wait, wait it's coming back.
- May I touch your hair?
又来到下面 等着 它又回来喽
我可以摸你的头发吗
You want to touch my hair?
你要摸我的头发
Um...Sure.
好吧
You should be practicing as your dad told you.
你爸爸希望你在这儿好好练琴啊
I'm practicing.
我是在练啊
刚才所谓的练习根本用不上这些
- What you're doing, you won't be needing these.
- What's your problem?
你干什么
Leave it.
别碰
Don't bother about me.
Oughta bother more about your own business.
我不需要你管 你应该多管你自己的事情
You dad will be mad if he knows.
你爸爸知道会很生气的
Are you sick? You're not my dad!
你有毛病啊 你又不是我爸爸
Come on, dude.
你这家伙想干嘛
What now?
怎么啦
- You're not my dad.
- Gather your stuff and go home right now.
- 你又不是我爸爸
- 马上收拾好你的东西回家
我叫你别碰
I said, leave it.
Better mind you own business.
I will tell your father.
- 你管好你自己就可以了
- 我会告诉你父亲的
加油
Let me go!
放开我
He is American. He just moved here. He doesn't
know who you are. Please don't beat him...
他是美国人 他刚搬过来
他不知道你是谁 请不要打他
Get off!
走开
Stop beating him!
别打了
That's enough. Don't beat him any more.
He did nothing bad.
够了 不要打他了 他什么坏事都没做
要打架吗
You want to fight?
Let me go. That's enough.
放开我 够了
That's enough. Don't fight any more.
够了 不要再打啦
你还好吗 让我看看
- Are you okay?
- Leave me alone.
别管我 我没事
I'm fine.
- Dre, dude...
- Leave me alone.
德瑞
拜托 别管我
Dre, are you ready?
Cause we got to be there in like 20 minutes.
德瑞 你好了吗
我们20分钟内一定要到
I know, mom.
知道了 妈
你穿制服了吧
- And you have your uniform on, right?
- Yes, mom.
穿了 妈
Don't break any rules
on the first day.
第一天一定要遵守规定
Okay, come on, I'm waiting for you.
好了
快点 还在等你
Wait, you don't have to comin', I mean...
I can handle it.
妈 其实你不用送我 我自己没问题
Dre, don't be silly, it's your first day.
别傻了 德瑞 今天是你的第一天
Plus, we both have to meet the
assist principal Mrs. Pong.
而且我们需要一起见副校长包太太
I can find her.
You need to get to work, right?!
我找得到她 你需要赶快去上班 不是吗
- Are you trying to get rid of me?
- No, mom.
你想赶走我吗
不是啦 妈
Mrs. Pong.
Hi, Mrs. Pong.
包太太
你好 包太太
- Mrs. Parker,  we've been waiting.
- I'm so sorry we are late...
帕克太太 我们一直在等您
对不起 我们迟到了
昨晚才从底特律飞来的
We just flew from Detroit last night...
- And this is my son Dre.
- Hello.
这是我的儿子 德瑞
- 你好
- 您好
- We only wear uniforms on Uniform day.
- Oh, that's my fault.
我们只在制服日穿制服
哦 那是我的错
I didn't have a chance to read the school packages
sent to me. Will be better tomorrow.
还没来得及读校规
明天会更好的
- And hats are not permitted.
- Yeah, I should've read up on the dress code.
不能戴帽子的
我应该先读一下着装要求的
- Dre, is that make-up? What is that?
- Mom, I ran into a pole.
德瑞 你化妆了吗 这是什么
妈 我撞到了一根柱子
- No, you have a black eye. You've got into a fight?
- Fighting is not tolerated here.
这明明是熊猫眼 你打架了
这里不允许打架
You heard him, he ran into a pole.
Come here, Dre.
您也听到啦 他撞到了柱子 过来 德瑞
- Mom, don't start.
- Who did it?
- 妈 别这样
- 是谁干的
没人 妈 我撞到了柱子
没告诉你 就因为你会这样
Nobody mom, I ran into a pole. I ain't tell
you cause I know you would react like this.
Dre, you know I don't play,
if somebody hit my baby, I would tear...
德瑞 你是知道的
要是有人敢动我的宝贝儿子 我就
I know mom,
that's why I don't tell you stuff.
我知道 妈 所以我什么也没说
- Just relax, I just ran into a...
- Yeah, yeah,  you ran into a pole.
放心 我就是撞到了一根柱子
对 对 你撞到了一根柱子
Alright Dre, alright, alright. Look, go to class,
go to  class, but we will talk about this later.
好吧 德瑞 去上课吧
先去上课 这件事晚点再说
Okay? Alright, go!
好吗 去吧
- I love you.
- Mom?!
我爱你
妈
I said I love you.
我说我爱你
- Okay, I love you too.
- Okay, have a good day.
我也爱你 行了吧
好的 祝你有个美好的一天
- Hi.
- Hey!
你好
You know,
we only wear uniforms on Uniform day.
你知道吗 我们只在制服日才穿制服
Oh yeah, I still got that one.
嗯 我刚知道
Thanks.
谢谢
- I'm Meiying.
- I'm Dre.
我叫美莹
我叫德瑞
Sorry about Cheng.
关于程的事 对不起
So that's his name?!
原来他叫程
- Is he your boyfriend?
- No.
他是你男朋友吗
不是
- Our parents are very close.
- He definitely likes you.
我们的父母很熟
他一定喜欢你
- I have to go practice.
- Wait...
我要去练习了
等一下 你一边吃饭一边练习
- You eat and practice at the same time?
- Yes.
对啊
But, my mom says if you eat standing up,
it gives you gas.
可是我妈说如果你站着吃饭 就会放屁
You're funny.
你很搞笑
- Come to fix the hot water.
- It's in there.
我来修热水
在那里面
Kid?
Kid?!
孩子 孩子
Did you just hit me in my neck
with a toothpaste cap?!
你刚刚用牙膏帽击中我的脖子吗
Hot water fine.
Flip switch.
热水没坏 转这个开关
Wait half hour, take shower,
flip switch off.
等半小时洗澡
关上开关
Why don't you just leave it on?
为什么不让它开着
- You leave on in America?
- We don't have a switch in America.
你们在美国一直开着它
在美国没有这个开关吗
Get switch,
Save planet.
装上开关 保护地球
- What happened to your eye?
- I ran into a pole.
你眼睛怎么了
我撞到了一根柱子
Interesting pole.
有意思的柱子
- Dre?! I'm back.
- That's my mom.
- 德瑞 我回来了
- 那是我妈
门把手也有问题
End it, do the handle, it's messed up.
- Are you ready for school?
- Yeah.
- 你准备好上学了吗
- 好了
- Hey, let me help you.
- They have your favorite cereal here, I found it.
- 你去哪里了
- 我找到了你最喜欢的麦片
Dre, for the one hundredth time,
can you please pick up your jacket?
德瑞
第一百次问你了
能不能把你的外套捡起来
- One second, mom.
- No! Not in one second, now!
- 等一下 妈
- 不行
不能等 现在
This programme is about to be over.
Give me two minutes.
这个节目马上结束了 给我两分钟
Dre, I don't care!
Come and pick it up now.
德瑞 我不管现在 把它给我捡起来
- God, how many times do I have to ask you?
- Once.
天啊 我到底要告诉你多少次
一次
- That's right. Make it happen.
- "What's with you and the jacket?!"
- 对 说了就要做
- “我到底要…”
- I'm sorry, what was that?
- Nothing.
- 你说什么
- 没事
最好没事
Okay, just what I thought...
Nothing.
Thank you.
谢谢
好 再来一遍
From the top again.
Okay. It's enough please. You are rushing it.
You must play the pauses.
可以了 停
你太急了
要懂得停顿
Do you know how important this is for your family?
What it will mean for your life?
你知道这对你家人来说有多重要吗
对你的人生有多重要
We have to work this weekend.
I'm calling you father.
这个周末我们需要继续练习
我现在打给你爸爸
We continue.
继续练习
你叫什么名字
- How that sound?
- Almost like a Chinese.
怎么样
很像中文
Yeah, I'm fluent. And I don't know about that guy
was talking about? I thought you sounded great.
当然 我很流利
我不知道那个男的说了什么
但我觉得你拉得很棒
Thank you.
谢谢
- So, you are practicing for anything? Like a show?
- Yes, I have an audition next month...
所以你在为什么练习 为表演
是的 为了下个月北京音乐学院的试演
- For the Beijing Academy of Music.
- Beijing Academy of Music. Sounds important.
北京音乐学院 听起来很重要
You know, their initials spell BAM.
你知道吗
它的大写字母拼起来是“bam”
What?
什么
好的
I gotta go.
我得赶快走了
喂
Can I touch your hair?
我可以摸你的头发吗
You're gonna do something?
怎样
Just stay away from us.
离我们远一点
All of us.
我们全部
Baby?!
宝贝
Dre, are you sleeping?
德瑞 你睡着了吗
你能不能签一下这个
- Um, can you sign this?
- For the Forbidden City?!
你要去紫禁城
I think it's funny that you have to give
my permission to go to the Forbidden City.
我觉得挺好笑的
你要得到我的允许去紫“禁”城
- Pole in Beijing.
- Not funny, mom.
是北京的两极化嘛
一点都不好笑 妈
Oh, cut it out, grumpy.
唉呀 你这个坏脾气的孩子
我认真的 德瑞 这个冰淇淋
I'm serious, Dre. This ice cream,
I don't know what they do it,
不知道为什么 比较有味道
but it's more flavoristic. What?
什么 妈 这就是你
Mom, this is you. "Oh my goodness, this ice cream
here is so good, and everything in China...
“天啊 这冰淇淋太美味了
“所有在中国的一切都比以前好”
is so much better than everything else..."
Aw, mom c'mon...
拜托你 妈
First of all, I don't sound like that,
and I don't move all like that.
我可没像你说的那么夸张
You should get some ice cream, sweetie.
我应该给你买点冰淇淋的 真的很不错
- Mom, mom,  c'mon.
- Dre! Wait!
- 妈 跟我过来
- 德瑞
- 妈 快点
Boy, you won't get running from me?!
这孩子 就这样跑掉 还想和老妈赛跑吗
天啊
Kung Fu.
功夫
What do we learn here?
你们都学到了什么
不能软弱 不能痛苦 不能心软
No weakness! No pain! No mercy!
开始
敬礼
Begin!
起立
嗨 亲爱的
妈 快点 咱们走吧
- Mom, mom, c'mon, let's go. C'mon, mom!
- What? Dre, we just got here.
什么 德瑞 我们才刚到这
快点 妈
- Dre, what's going on?
- Nothing.
德瑞 怎么了
没事
- Dre, what happened?
- Nothing happened.
德瑞 发生了什么事
没事
What is it, you don't want to take that class?
Whatever Dre, What happened?
怎么了 你不想上那个功夫班吗
德瑞 到底怎么了
We moved to China!
That's what happened!
我们搬来了中国
就是这件事
好 等一下
Okay, stop.
Don't be like that, Dre.
不要这样 德瑞
What do you want me to do?
你想要我怎么做
我们到这还没超过一星期
- We've been here less than a week...
- I feel like it's a year!
我感觉像一年了
I hate it here.
我讨厌这里
Dre, please let me help you.
德瑞 让我帮助你
I can't help you if you don't tell
me what's wrong?! Oh, please.
如果你不告诉我怎么了 我无法帮助你
You don't care what's wrong!
你根本不在乎到底哪里不对劲了
All you care about is how happy I am
and how great ice cream is.
你只在乎“我有多开心”和“冰淇淋有多好吃”
I'm not happy.
I hate it here!
我一点都不开心
我讨厌这里
I want to go home!
我想回家
Dre, we can't go home. Okay?
There is nothing left for us in Detroit.
德瑞 我们没法回家 懂吗
我们在底特律什么也没有了
This is what we've got.
就是这样了
This is home.
这里就是我们的家
好吗
同学们 在这里集合
Gather on here.
Welcome to one of the most popular
landmarks in all over China.
欢迎来到全中国最受欢迎的地标
It is visited by millions of people
every year.
这是全世界游客所向往的地方
The Forbidden City.
紫禁城
You press them for good luck.
摸它会带给你好运
- I wish someone would just...
- Yeah, me too.
真希望有人可以制止他
嗯 我也是
- Just tell someone.
- Yeah, I got it.
告诉谁吧
嗯 我会的 谢谢
Thanks a lot.
The walls of the palace were reinforced
with the bricks, 15 layers deep,
皇宫的地板有十五层厚
to prevent anyone
from coming in.
防止有人从地下潜入
- Mr. Parker... Is everything okay?
- Oh yes?
帕克同学 您好
你没什么事吧
Um...Yes, thank you.
嗯 谢谢
可真够壮观的 回家一定要把它写下来
走吧
走开 走开
走开 走开 别在这里玩了 快点走开
谁啊 站住 别跑
Get him.
站住 别跑
Come on.
站住
这边 这边
别跑
这是我的屋顶啊
快 追上他
快追
站住
在这里 在这里
站住 往哪里跑
快 别跑 别跑
想跑 看你往哪跑
You're fast.
你很快
But not fast enough.
不够快
He's had enough.
算了 程 够了
Don't you remember what we learned?
你忘记我们学什么了吗
No weakness. No pain.
真的够了 别打了
No mercy!
走开
回家
来
Go home.
回家
- What's up with the light bulbs, Mr. Han?
- Shh!
这些灯泡是干嘛用的
I thought you are just a maintenance man?
我以为你只是一个维修工
You've seen only with your eyes,
so you are easy to fool.
你只用你的眼睛思考 所以很容易被骗
It doesn't hurt.
一点都不疼
Jiao Fa, ancient Chinese healing.
角法 中国古法治疗
How did you do that up there? You like even
didn't punch them. They...beat each other up.
你刚刚怎么做到的 你好像都没有出手
他们就自己打倒自己了
When fighting angry, blind men...
当你的对手是愤怒而盲目的
best we just stay out of the way.
最好的做法就是避开他
- So, where did you learn Kung Fu?
- From father.
你从哪里学的功夫
我父亲
Have you ever taught anybody?
你有教过任何人吗
No.
没有
Would you?
你愿意吗
- Depends.
- On what?
- 看情况
- 看什么情况
- Reason.
- What about to kick somebody's ass?
理由
例如想要揍扁一个人的屁股
The best fights are the ones we avoid.
避免是最好的战斗方式
What if I wanna avoid getting
my ass kicked?
如果我想避免的是屁股被揍呢
- Stop saying "ass".
- Sorry.
- 别再说“屁股”
- 对不起
Kung Fu is for knowledge, defense.
功夫是一种学识 防守
Not to make war,
but to create peace.
不为战争 只为和平
That's not definitely what they're taught.
那绝对不是他们所学到的
No such thing as bad student,
only bad teacher.
没有坏学生 只有坏老师
That's great. I guess we'll just stroll in
their school and talk to their teacher.
对 太好了
我们可以晃进他们学校找那位老师谈谈喽
- Good idea.
- No, bad idea.
- 好主意
- 不 一点都不好
If I go in there, I get my ass kick...
我去那里 一定会屁股挨揍
- I'll get beat up.
- You got beat up anyway.
我一定会被揍
反正你去不去都会被揍
Would you go with me?
你会和我一起去吗
No, sorry.
不 对不起
- But you said it was a good idea.
- For you, bad idea for me.
但是你刚刚说好主意的
对你来说是 对我来说可不是
C'mon, it's not like you should be busy
or anything...I don't even speak Chinese.
拜托 你又不是很忙
而且我根本不会讲中文
Very sorry.
非常抱歉
Okay...Whatever.
好吧
那算了
Wait!
等下
What are you doing?
Why did you stop?
怎么了 为什么不打
Finish!
起
Okay, Mr. Han, let's get out of here.
好了 韩先生 我们可以走了
归队
We do not stop when our enemy is down!
就算是对手倒在台上也不能停手
No mercy.
你们都不能停 继续攻击到底
No mercy in the studio.
No mercy in life.
直到摧毁对手的意志
What are you looking at?
你看什么呢
He's the one that attacked me.
师傅 就那个人打了我们
We are here to make peace.
我们道歉的
Let your little thing mind himself.
让那个小东西管好自己吧
One to one, no problem...Six to one,
too much to ask of anyone.
一对一 不是问题
你们四个打一个就有点欺负人
I see.
明白了
Prepare for match!
准备比武
Whoa Mr. Han, does he want us to fight?
等一下 韩先生 他要和我们打吗
We are not here to fight.
我们不是来打架的
你欺负了我的学生 今天又到这里来挑战
You attack my students
and disrespect my studio?!
想走 哪那么容易
You want to leave?
Not so easy.
Master Li...
李师傅
You both came here.
要不就你来
One of you fights now.
你们两个一定有一个要参加比武
The boy will fight there.
要比上那比
OPEN KUNG FU TOURNAMENT
We accept your challenge.
好 我接受你的挑战
Please instruct your students
to leave my boy alone to train.
好 从现在开始
请你的学生不要骚扰我的徒弟
Attention!
听着
From now on the little thing
is to be left alone...
从现在开始 谁都不许骚扰这小东西
until the tournament.
直到武术大赛 明白吗
- Understood?!
- Yes!
明白
哎
If he does not show up
for the competition...
武术大赛的时候如果他不来
I will bring pain to him and you.
那你就是孬种
所以 一切像你计划般的顺利吗
So, that go pretty much
how you planned it?
There's good news and bad news.
有好消息和坏消息
The good news is they promised
to leave you alone.
好消息是他们不会再骚扰你
- Really?
- While you prepare.
真的
在你准备的过程中
Prepare for what?
准备什么
The tournament.
You'll fight them all, one by one.
比赛
你会和他们一对一的比武
Huh?
So the bad news is now
they get to beat me up in public.
所以坏消息是
他们可以让我在公开场合挨揍了
- Yes.
- Great. Thanks. Thanks a lot.
是的 太好了 谢谢 十分感谢
They're gonna kill me.
You saw their Kung Fu.
他们会杀了我的 你看过他们的功夫
That's not Kung Fu. That does not
represent China.
那根本不是中国功夫 更不能代表中国
That bad man teach them really bad
things that hurt, a lot.
可是那个坏人教的很厉害 真的很厉害
More good news.
I will teach you real Kung Fu.
还有一个好消息
我会教你真正的功夫
Yes.
太棒了
帕克
- See you later, mom.
- Hey, wait. This is early for you for a Saturday.
一会儿见 妈
等一下 星期六这么早 你上哪去
- Mr. Han will teach me Kung Fu.
- The maintenance man?
韩先生要教我功夫
那个维修工
It's China mom,
everybody knows Kung Fu.
这里是中国 妈 所有的人都懂功夫
Dre, you know how do I feel about
your fighting.
德瑞 你知道我对你打架的感觉
Kung Fu is not fight mom, it's about
making peace with your enemy.
功夫不是打架 妈 是和你的敌人和解
- Be careful, Dre.
- Yeah.
小心点 德瑞 知道了
Mr. Han?
韩先生
- Mr. Han?
- Back here.
韩先生
在后面
You know you have a car
in your living room, Mr. Han?
你知道吗 你的客厅里有台车子 韩先生
Okay, I was thinking about yesterday. I know
I was kinda freaking out about the tournament...
好吧 我昨天一直在想
我知道关于比赛我有些害怕
but I realized something last night.
但是我昨天想明白了
I'm an athlete. My number one asset
is I'm fast, okay?!
我是一个运动员
而且我最大的优势就是我很快 对吧
I'm quick. I'm quick.
Got the speed. Cat speed.
我很快 明白吗 很快 速度 来抓我
You see? I'm quick yeah, you see?
In the US, I used to take gymnastic at PAL,
看 我很快吧
看 我曾经在警察体育联盟学过体育
that's Police Athletic League, to check it,
right?
那可是警察体育联盟 看看 准备好了吗
Boom. You see that?
噢 你看到了吗 看到了吗
看见了
My Uncle Reymi used to date that
Brazilian girl and he learned Jiu-Jitsu.
我的叔叔瑞米曾经与一个巴西女孩约会
然后他学了柔术 还教了我一些
And he taught some of it to me.
As like, locks and holds and stuff, it's okay.
好像是锁挡之类的招数 试试攻击我
Attack me.
You see that? Feel that?
I can break it.
看见了吧 我可以伤到你
I'm choosing not to.
To press your luck. It's dangerous.
不过我不会 这叫压力锁 很危险
And he also taught me Capoeira so...
他还教了我卡泼卫勒舞 你看
Can't touch me. Can't touch...
你碰不到我 你碰不到我
Was that antique?
那是古董吗
Pick up your jacket.
捡起你的外套
So basically Mr. Han,
what I'm trying to say is...
基本上 韩先生 我想说的是
I got a good foundation here.
You know, like I said. I'm just...
我底子很好的 你知道 就像我说的我
Might not be as hard to teach me
as other people, you know.
可能教我不会像教别人那么难
- Hang it up.
- Okay.
挂起来
好
- Happy now?
- Take it down.
好 但是现在
拿下来
- You just...
- Take it down.
可是你刚刚
拿下来
Put it on.
穿上
Take it off.
脱掉
- I already did all of this.
- Take it off.
- 我都刚做过…
- 脱掉
Can you just tell me,
why I'm doing this?
- 你可不可以告诉我为什么…
- 脱掉
Take it off.
Hang it up.
挂起来
Take it down.
拿下来
Put it on the ground.
放在地上
Pick it up.
捡起来
Hang up.
挂起来
Take it down.
拿下来
Put it on.
穿上
Take it off.
脱掉
Put it on the ground.
放在地上
Pick it up.
捡起来
Hang it up.
挂起来
Take it down.
Put it on.
拿下来
穿上
Take it off.
脱掉
Hang it up.
挂起来
Mr. Han, why do you have
a car in your living room?
韩先生
为什么你的客厅里有一台车
No street parking.
街上没有停车位
Hey!
嗨
So how did it go?
What you learned?
学得怎么样 学到了什么
Nothing.
没有
Uniform on Uniform day.
制服日穿制服
- You're fighting in the tournament?
- Yeah, how did you hear?
你要参加比赛
对 你从哪听来的
Everybody knows.
所有人都知道
- I hope you have a good teacher.
- Yeah, me too.
我希望你有个好老师
嗯 我也希望
He's a maintenance man.
他是个维修工
- Can I ask you a question?
- Yes.
- 我能问你个问题吗
- 可以
Well, I know you're practicing, and I think I'm practicing, I mean,
I don't know what I'm doing...
我知道你在练习
我认为我也在练习
我的意思是 我虽然不知道我在练什么
- But, we both kind of practicing, you know and...
- Are you going to that Shi-Shi festival?
我们既然都需要练习 唉
你要去七夕游园会吗
Yeah, I mean, I've missed
the Shi-Di Festival since I've been in China.
当然 我来到中国后
还没有错过任何一个“七夕”游园会呢
- Go to the Shaolin theater.
- Okay. You want me to meet you?
到时去皮影戏院
好 在那里见你
Oh, oh, so like Shaolin theater, okay Shi-Fi-Shi festival.
Shaolin theater, okay. Cool.
好 皮影戏院 知道了
“七夕”节 皮影戏院
好 知道了
- When is it again?
- Tomorrow. The show starts at seven.
好 什么时候来着
明天 表演七点开始
Okay. So tomorrow, Shaolin theater.
Shi-Shi festival at seven.
好 明天 皮影戏院 七夕节 7点
- See you tomorrow.
- Shi-Shi festival.
明天见
“七夕”节
- Festival. - Shi-Shi festival.
- Okay. - Okay.
节日
“七夕”节
好 好
Mr. Han?
韩先生
- Mr. Han, can I come in?
- You may come in.
- 我可以进来吗
- 你可以进来
Where's your jacket?
你的外套呢
- I thought, I was warmin' up without it.
- Go get it.
我以为不冷 不用穿了
回去拿
You want me to go
all way back, just to get it?
你要我大老远回去就为拿那件外套
Yes, all the way back
where you hide it.
对 去你藏外套的地方拿
- This is not right.
- What? I'm doing it.
这样不对
干嘛 我在做了
No.
不对
- Something is missing.
- Nothing is missing.
少了点什么
没有少什么
You forgot, this.
你忘记了这样
Attitude.
态度
Shake it off.
脱下外套
好
Attitude.
Yes, that's it.
态度
对 那才像样
Okay, Mr. Han. I get it. I'm sorry.
I shouldn't have treated my mom like that.
好啦 韩先生 我明白了 对不起
我不应该那样对我妈 你是对的
You're right.
- Put it on the ground.
- Hello.
放在地上
有人吗
Ow, hey mom.
Um, did you get the tickets?
妈妈
你买到票了吗
Yes, I got the tickets,
and I got an extra one for Mr. Han.
嗯 我买好了票
我帮韩先生多买了一张
- But I didn't say...
- Dre, stop it.
但是 我没让你
德瑞 闭嘴
Mr. Han, would you like to go with us
to the Shi-Shi festival?
韩先生
你愿意和我们一起去“七夕”游园会吗
No, thank you.
Too many people.
不用了 谢谢 人太多
- Yeah, mom. Way too many people.
- Yeah, but I already bought the tickets.
对 妈 人太多了
但是我票已经买好了
- I don't go...
- Mr. Han, I'm not taking "no" for an answer.
- 我不去…
- 韩先生 我不接受你这个回答
You'll have fun. You need
to get out the house, okay?
一定会很好玩的
离开房子出去晃晃吧 好吗
Here are your clothes, Dre.
Come on, hurry up and change.
你的衣服 德瑞 快点 换衣服去
Dre...
德瑞
Pick up your jacket!
把你的外套捡起来
You were right Mr. Han,
there are a lot of people here.
你是对的 韩先生 这里太多人了
Chinese Valentine's Day.
七夕是中国的情人节
这实在太美了
Yeah, Mom. I'm going to go get something
to eat, then going to go to the bathroom.
是啊 妈
我去买点吃的 然后去上个厕所
Be back, right here,
in 20 minutes.
二十分钟后回到这里
好
- I love you.
- I love you, too. Be careful. 20 minutes.
- 我爱你
- 我也爱你 注意安全
二十分钟
- 20.
- Okay.
- 二十
- 好
- 你好
I got this, and this for you.
我带了这个送给你
I downloaded this.
It has a very cool violins stuff, and I...
我录制的 很好听的 有很多小提琴曲
I thought maybe you could play along and...
It's not like Bach and...
我觉得你可以边听边拉
没有像巴赫那么厉害
but, I thought maybe
you'd like it and...
但是我觉得你应该会喜欢的
谢谢
- So, um, do you have any kids?
- No.
你有孩子吗
没有
Oh, how's Dre doing?
那你觉得德瑞现在学得怎么样
- Um, Shao Dre making a progress.
- Shao Dre?
小德瑞在进步
“小”德瑞
Yes, Chinese pollito.
是的 中文的“小”
So, um, how many students do you have?
那你一共有多少学生呢
- Including Shao Dre?
- Yeah.
- 包括小德瑞吗
- 嗯
One.
一个
So, what's the show about?
这场戏是在讲什么呢
It's the story of the Goddess...
这是关于一个女神的故事
and a boy she loves.
和她爱的男孩
I love this story.
我非常喜欢这个故事
Her mother does not approve of him.
她妈妈不接受他
So, she cuts a wide river in the sky
to separate them forever.
所以她在天空中划出一道银河
让他们永远分离
But once a year,
all the birds in the sky...
但是每一年天空中所有的鸟儿
felt sad for them,
and they form a bridge.
都为他们而悲伤 所以鸟儿们组成一座桥
So the two of them may be
together for a single night.
让他们两个可以相聚一晚
I'll be there at you audition,
if you come to my tournament.
如果你来看我的比赛 我也去看你的试演
- Okay, I'll be there.
- Pinky swear.
好 我会去的
拉勾勾
See, you wrap your hands like this.
看 你要把手这样
I swear that I'll be there at your audition,
no matter what happens.
我发誓不论发生什么事
我一定会去看你试演的
And I promise to cheer bigger
than anyone else when you win.
我也发誓当你赢得比赛时
我会比谁都大声的为你欢呼
What up, Mr. Han?
你在干嘛 韩先生
Did I say come in?
我有说“进来”吗
Um, I think you did. I mean...
我以为你说了
- Mr. Han, can I please come in?
- Yes.
韩先生 我可以进来了吗
可以
- So, what we are doing today?
- Same.
所以 我们今天要做什么
一样
Mr. Han, I told you. I get it, okay?
Be respectful! I got it!
你知道 韩先生 我告诉你了
我懂了 好不好
要有礼貌 我真的懂了
I put my jacket on a thousand times,
and I took it off a thousand times, okay?
我已经穿了一千次外套 脱了一千次了
This is stupid. I'm done!
这真的很白痴 我不玩了
Let them beat me up,
if they want to.
他们要揍我就揍好了
You know why you only have
one student? 'Cause you don't know Kung Fu.
你现在明白为什么你只有一个学生了吧
因为你根本不懂功夫
- Shao Dre!
- What?
小德瑞
干嘛
Come here.
到这儿来
- Jacket on!
- Mr. Han, I already...- Jacket on!
穿上外套
- 韩先生 我已经和你说过了…
- 穿上外套
- Jacket on!
- I don't have a jacket...- Jacket on!
穿上外套
- 我现在没有穿外套…
- 穿上外套
Be strong.
要用力
Jacket on.
穿上外套
Firm.
稳住
Jacket off.
脱外套
Remember...
记住 要一直用力
always strong...
Jacket off.
脱掉外套
Strong.
用力
Left foot back.
Right foot back.
左脚退后 右脚退后
Left foot back.
Pick up your jacket!
左脚退后 捡起你的外套
- Whoa, Mr. ...- Focus!
- Okay. - Always concentrate.
- 哦 韩先生
- 专心
- 好的
- 一定要专心
Left back. Right foot back.
Pick up your jacket!
左退
右脚退后 捡起你的外套
Stay.
别动
Pick up your jacket.
捡起你的外套
Strong.
用力
Hang it up.
挂起来
挂起来 还有态度
And attitude!
Strike!
攻击
Hang up and attitude!
挂起来 还有态度
Harder.
重些 再重些
Good, but no face.
很好
不要做鬼脸
Jacket off!
脱掉外套
Kung Fu lives in everything
we do, Shao Dre.
功夫 就在我们的生活中 小德瑞
It lives in how we put on a jacket,
and how we take off the jacket.
它就在我们如何穿起外套 如何脱掉外套
It lives in
how we treat people.
也在我们如何对待他人中
Everything is Kung Fu.
所有的一切都是功夫
- So, why do not we take the Shiroko?
- I don't drive the Shiroko.
为什么我们不开那台“尚酷”
我不开那台“尚酷”
- Do you have a license?
- Yes.
你有驾照吗
有
So you have a license and a car
and we're in the train?
你有驾照有车 但是我们坐火车
- Please, be quiet.
- I'm just sayin'...
请安静
我只是说那样会省很多钱
seems like we could've saved
a lot of money, don't you think?
你说呢
- Do you always ask these many questions?
- I'm sorry.
你总是问这么多问题吗
对不起
So, what we are learning today?
所以我们今天学什么
Chi.
气
Eternal Energy.
The essence of life.
体内的能量
生命的动力
It moves inside of us,
flows through our bodies.
它在我们体内流动
Give us power from within.
给予我们内在的力量
I get it,
like the "Force" from Star Wars.
我明白了
像星球大战中的力
You're Yoda,
and I'm like... I'm like a Jedi.
你是尤达大师 而我是
我像是一个绝地武士
北沟村
谢谢
- Is this where you learned Kung Fu?
- Yes.
你是在这里学到功夫的吗
对
Everything good about me
was born here.
我身上所有好的东西都来自于这里
So Dre, you gotta leave your backpack
and skateboard here.
小德瑞 你可以把书包和滑板放在这里
- So, where are we going?
- The journey to the top of the mountain.
所以我们要去哪里
我们要登上山顶
Tomb of the Dragon Well.
饮龙泉水
Dragon Well? It's probably,
closer than it is, I'm looking at it.
龙泉
可能那里比看起来要近吧
Right?
对不对
- Are we there yet?
- Soon.
我们到了没有
很快
- How do you say water in Chinese?
- Shui.
中文的“水”怎么说
水
I need some shui.
我需要水
I'm really thirsty.
我真的很渴
- I'm thirsty, Mr. Han.
- Water on top of the mountain.
我渴了 韩先生
水在山顶
Shao Dre.
小德瑞
The journey is complete.
就走到这里
- This is the Dragon Well?
- Yes.
这里就是龙泉
对
I stood here with my father,
when I was your age.
我曾和我的父亲站在这里
在我还是你这么大的时候
He told me that's the magic
Kung Fu water.
他告诉我这是神奇的功夫之水
You drink and nothing
can defeat you.
你喝完后 没有任何事能打到你
It's the best water I've ever tasted.
这是我喝过最好喝的水
- Did you see the lady with the snake?
- Yes.
你有没有看到那个和蛇在一起的女人
- 有
- 她在练蛇功吧
She was doing the Cobra thing.
She was like...
她模仿着蛇 好像 有这么近
copying the snake. And it was like...
right here, and she was like...
然后她这样
You did not watch closely enough,
Shao Dre.
你没有仔细看清楚 小德瑞
The snake was copying the woman.
是蛇在模仿那个女人
What? I don't get it.
什么 我不懂
Look.
看
- What do you see?
- Me, well my reflection. - Yes.
- 你看到什么
- 自己
- 我的倒影
- 对
- Now, what do you see?
- It's blurry. - Yes.
现在你看到了什么
- 模糊了
- 对
The woman was like still water
quiet and calm.
那个女人就好像静止的水
默然 平静
In here and in here.
在这里和这里
所以 蛇反映她动静 有如静止的水一般
So, the snake reflects her action,
like still water.
- Like a mirror?
- Yes.
- 像一面镜子
- 对
So, she controlled a snake
by doing nothing?
所以她什么都不做 却可以控制蛇
Being still and doing nothing,
are two very different things.
静止和什么都不做是完全不同的
- She used her Chi on that snake, didn't she?
- Very good.
她用了她的气在蛇身上 对吗
不错
You gotta teach me that.
How to control people.
你必须要教会我 那个 如何去控制别人
There is only one person
you need to learn how to control.
你只需要学会去控制一个人
Who?
谁
Empty your mind.
Flow with my movement.
让你的头脑放空 跟着我的动作移动
Connect to the energy,
around you.
感受到你周围的能量
- I kinda just want to learn the cobra thing.
- Cobra takes a lifetime.
我只想学那个蛇功
蛇功需要一辈子的时间
- Requires great focus.
- But I have great focus?!
需要专心致志
我很专心啊
- Oh my God. Mr. Han...
- Your focus,
天啊 韩先生
你需要更专心
- needs more focus.
- Mr. Han...
韩先生
Thank you, Mr. Han.
谢谢你 韩先生
There's no such thing
as fortune cookies in China.
中国是没有幸运饼干这类玩意的
Dre, please be careful
crossing the street.
德瑞 过马路时小心点
You just scared the life out of me,
the other day. They have the "right-of-way".
你那天吓死我了
看什么呢
And the symbols. I can't get
the symbols right on the bathrooms.
还有那些标志 我真搞不懂厕所的标志
And I'm still walkin' into the men's restroom.
那天我竟然走进了男厕所
The other day I walked in,
there was this 90 years old Chinese man,
还有一天我走进去
里面有个90多岁的老头
he thought he was getting a little treat.
他以为他碰到好运了呢
Dre, please stop that! You look crazy!
Here, eat your noodles!
德瑞 请不要这样 你看起来好恐怖
快吃你的面
起来
Mr. Han,
what's goin' on?
韩先生 你在干嘛
Anticipation.
料敌
I can't see...
我不行
Don't see it, feel it.
不要用看的 用感觉
Dammit, Mr. Han!
可恶 韩先生
I felt that one!
我感觉到那一下了
- Mr. Han.
- What?
- 韩先生
- 干嘛
- Concentrate, okay?
- Okay. Do I get the stick now?
专心 行吗
行 现在轮到我使棍子了吧
转 踢
- Dre, you okay?
- I'm okay.
- 德瑞 你没事吧
- 我没事
What's up Mr. Han, what time
we are trainin' tomorrow?
韩先生 我们明天几点训练
小德瑞 我们明天没有训练
Shao Dre, we are not training tomorrow.
Why not?
为什么没有
- Wu chi pi fan
- Wu chi pi fan?
物极必反
It means: "Too much of something
is not good."
意思是“太多了反而不好”
You train a lot, you need to rest.
你练了很多 你需要休息
A day off?
Yes, Mr. Han! Yes!
休息一天
对 韩先生 对呀
Shao Dre needs to rest.
Yes, Mr. Han.
小德瑞需要休息
好 韩先生 你也要休息
You rest, too.
I love you, Mr. Han. Peace!
爱你 韩先生 再见
你好
Are you okay?
你怎么了
- My audition is tomorrow at a six.
- Isn't it what you've been practicing for?
我的试演是明天六点
你不是为它练习很久了吗
- Yes, of course.
- Don't worry, you got it.
是的 当然了
不要担心 你可以的
What if they don't pick me?
如果他们没选中我呢
Meiying, wait!
美莹 等一下
好的 首先我会在那里陪你的
First of all,
I'm going to be there with you.
And B, all you have to do is what your
teacher says. Play the pauses.
第二 你只需要照老师教的做就行了
演奏时要懂得停顿 很简单的 看
It's easy, watch.
You see?
对不对
- I have to practice.
- Wait.
我要去练习了
等等
Wu gi bi fan.
乌鸡必番
What?
什么
I'm sorry,
I don't think you don't speak Chinese.
我开始认为你不懂中文了
Wu gi bi fan.
Too much of good stuff is a bad stuff?
乌鸡必番 太多好的等于坏的
Ow...Wu chi pi fan.
物极必反
Yeah.
Wu gi bi FUN.
没错 乌鸡必番
- Come on.
- Where are we going?
来吧
我们要去哪里 等等 不行啦
Have you ever been to the gym?
C'mon, we are going to have some fun.
走吧 我们要好好玩玩
Come on, I know you want
to go have some fun!
走吧 我知道你也想
Okay, that's going to give you
some serious gas.
好吧 这能让你产生一些严重的气体
- What do you see?
- Me.
你看到了什么
我自己
- Now, what do you see?
- Me.
现在看到了什么
我啊
Go, come on.
上去试试
You're dancing machine.
That was pretty good!
你是舞蹈达人 太棒了
Here comes, round two.
进入第二关
You're hot.
你太厉害了
- That's like American dancing.
Like, you should have a group.
- No.
这就像美国的舞蹈 你应该组个队伍
不
With like, other people in it
dancing behind you, doin' the same stuff.
你领舞 好多人在你后面跳相同的舞蹈
喂 对不起 我知道了
- The audition, it was changed to today.
- But they said, it's tomorrow.
试演改到了今天
- 但是他们说是明天的
- 出了状况
Something happened.
It is in 20 minutes.
只有二十分钟了
My father is coming to get me.
我爸现在来接我
你怎么想的你 你怎么搞的
对不起 借过
对不起 借过一下
她们到了
快点 快点
借过
Hey, she's like totally going to get it, right,
because that was just great.
她一定会进的 不是吗
因为刚刚演奏得很棒啊
Hey! That was fantastic.
嗨 刚刚棒极了
That was... You just...
You played so beautifully, and...
你刚刚演奏的好美
We can no longer be friends.
我们不能再作朋友了
You are bad for my life.
你对我影响不好
See you at the tournament.
比赛见喽
Don't be late for that.
不要迟到
妈妈：你在哪里赶快回家
Mr. Han!
韩先生
We'll not train today.
今天不练了
- What are you doing?
- It's July 8th.
你在干嘛
今天是七月八号
Why did you wreck the car?
你为什么要砸毁车子
His name was Kang Kang.
他的名字叫功功
Shao Dre, how old are you?
小德瑞 你几岁
Twelve.
十二
He was ten.
他当时十岁
He was so beautiful.
他可爱极了
Her name was Xiang.
她姓张
She was a singer.
她是一个歌手
Not professional.
不是专业的
She sang only for me.
她只为我而唱
What happened?
发生了什么事
There was a steep hill.
在一个很陡的山坡
Lots of rain.
下着大雨
The car, it just...
车子就
I was driving.
我开的车
We argued about something.
我们在争吵着什么
I was so angry.
我很生气
I lost control.
车子失控了
I try to remember...
我一直在努力回忆当时我们在吵什么
but I can not remember what we're
argued about.
I hope it was something important.
真希望是件很重要的事
Every year, I fix the car.
每一年我修车
But still fix nothing.
还是修不好任何东西
好 踢起来
好
Mr. Han!
韩先生
看着我 下去
再快
再跑一遍
来
Win or lose, doesn't matter.
Fight hard.
赢或输 并不重要
尽全力就好
Earn respect.
The boys leave you alone.
赢得尊重 那些孩子就不会再骚扰你了
I have a present for you.
有个礼物给你
Oh! Mr. Han.
韩先生
天啊
This is the one Bruce Lee had.
这套跟李小龙穿过的一样
Great.
太棒了
Thank you.
谢谢你
You have taught me
a very important lesson, Shao Dre.
你也教会我很重要的东西 小德瑞
Life will knock us down, but we can
choose, whether or not,  to get back up.
生活中的挫折会打倒我们
但是我们可以选择要不要重新站起来
You're the best friend
I've ever had, Mr. Han.
你是我最好的朋友 韩先生
Okay.
好了
Wait!
Can you help me with something?
等一下 你可以帮我一个忙吗
Dre?
德瑞
Is your dad home?
你爸在家吗
Sir...
陈先生
My name is Dre Parker.
我叫德瑞・帕克
My actions have brought
dishonor to your family.
我的行为
对您家是不尊重的
Your daughter has been
a great friend to me.
您的女儿曾经是我的好朋友
And from her I have learned...
她让我明白了
...that a true friend...
一个真正的朋友
...is a person
who makes your life better.
能让她的生活变得更好
But, if you give me a second chance...
我愿意接受任何惩罚
...I promise that I will be...
如果您能再给我一次机会
...the best friend your
daughter has ever had.
我保证成为
她真正的朋友
That's it.
就这样
她告诉我她承诺了
明天要去看你的比武大赛
我们家人从来不食言
My daughter told me that she made
a promise to be at your tournament.
我女儿告诉我她曾经答应去看你的比赛
In our family,
we do not break our promises.
在我们家 我们从不违背诺言
Good luck!
祝你好运
Thank you.
谢谢
Rock and roll.
来摇滚吧
Our audience, our friends here, welcome
现场的观众朋友们 大家好
Welcome to the Teenagers' Wushu Tournament.
欢迎来到青少年武术比赛的比赛现场
First let's welcome contestants from Wushu schools.
首先让我们欢迎武术学校的选手们
Today it's "friendship first, competition second,"
let's wait and see.
今天友谊第一 比赛第二
让我们拭目以待
Now, let the tournament begin!
好的 我们的比赛马上就要开始了
- The first match, please enter the ring.
- Thanks.
第一场 请上台 谢谢
You're up.
该我们了
- What's that?
- The rule book.
- 那是什么
- 比赛规则
- You don't know the rules?
- Of course I know the rules, it's simple.
- 你不知道规则
- 我当然知道
很简单 你打他 别让他打到你
You hit him,
and don't let him hit you.
What?
什么
Mr. Han, they're going to kill me.
韩先生 他们会打死我的
Two points to win. Win it two times.
Go. Focus. Focus.
两分获胜
去吧 打倒他两次
专心 专心 加油
敬礼
准备
开始
停 再出界就扣分了
That's a warning.
You cannot run off the mat.
那是一个警告
你不能离开毯子 下一次警告会输一分
Next time you lose a point.
Go.
去吧 要坚强
- Be strong.
- Come on, Dre.
加油 德瑞
开始
停
出界 犯规 蓝一分
赵1分    帕克0分
红方一分
赵1分    帕克1分
很好 下次 不要做鬼脸
- Good job. Next time, no face.
- I'm sorry, I can't help it.
- 对不起 我无法控制的
- 好啦 好啦
The next point winner.
打赢他
Come on, baby.
加油啊 宝贝
Go!
开始
Stop!
停
Ya!
太好了
The 2nd match, the red side wins.
第二局红方胜
Stop!
停
Ready!
准备
Go!
开始
The red side gets one point.
红方一分
That's my baby!
那是我的宝贝
The 1st set, the red side wins.
第一局 红方胜
Go.
上
梁涛    帕克
Go!
开始
Dre Parker advances to the semi-finals!
德瑞・帕克成功晋级半决赛
From now on, the semi-final matches,
three points to win.
从现在开始半决赛开始三分获胜
Be kinda hot if I
won this thing, huh, Mr. Han?
如果我赢了这个会很帅吧 韩先生
- Be kinda hot if you focused.
- Yeah, well, after that.
如果您能够专心会更帅
好啦 之后再说
And now the 1st semi-final
of the evening.
咱们到了我们今天本次武术大赛的
第一场半决赛的时间
那么我们的半决赛是
有来自龙腾武校的陆伟程
TOURNAMENT OF CHAMPIONS
SEMI-FINAL
First round:
Cheng Vs. Wu Ping.
对阵七星武校的吴平
开始
停
红方 赢
好的
停
红方陆伟程获胜
Cheng advances to final.
Next semi-final:
Introducing Fighting Dragon Liang...
下一场半决赛
是来自我们龙腾武校的梁子浩
小梁 你行的
...and the surprising finalist, Dre Parker.
还有他的对手 德瑞・帕克
Empty your mind. Focus.
放下所有杂念 专心
敬礼
准备
开始
You're disqualified!
出去 取消比赛资格
别动
小德瑞 你还好吗
Are you okay?
别动 别动
医生
严重吗
He's done.
他不能再比了
非常好 小勇士
You did very well, little warrior.
You've brought honor to your family.
你为你的家人带来了荣誉
The doctor says, you did great.
医生说你表现得非常好
谢谢
- You okay, baby?
- Yeah, I'm okay.
你还好吗 宝贝
嗯 我还好
如果在两分钟之后
他还没有回到我们的比赛现场
德瑞・帕克将不能继续参加我们的比赛了
Dre Parker has 2 minutes to
return to the match.
我们的龙腾武校将直接成为冠军
If he's unable to return...
...the Fighting Dragons
win by default.
我们看到了
今天现场有很多我们非常厉害的武校
Can you guys give us a second?
让我和韩先生单独待一会儿
Yeah, okay. Sure baby,
whatever you need.
好的
好 宝贝 你说怎样就怎样
Do you think I could have won?
你觉得我本来赢得了吗
Win or lose doesn't matter,
Shao Dre.
输赢不重要 小德瑞
You know that's not what I mean.
你知道我的意思的
Yes, I think you had a good chance.
是的 我觉得你机会很大
So, let's do the fiery cup thing.
那 我们来拔火罐吧
You don't need to fight anymore.
You have proven everything you need to prove.
你不需要再打了 你已经证明了自己
What, that I can get
beat up easy, and then quit?
证明什么 我那么容易被打败然后放弃
That's not balance,
that's not real Kung Fu.
那不是平衡 那不是真正的功夫
You said, when life knocks you down, you
could choose whether or not to get back up.
你说过 当生活把你打倒
你可以选择要不要再站起来
Well, I'm tryin' to get back up.
And why won't you help me?
那么我现在想再站起来 你为什么不帮我
Because...
因为我不能再看到你受伤了
I cannot watch you
get hurt anymore.
Please, Mr. Han. Please.
拜托 韩先生
拜托
Just tell me, Shao Dre. Why?
Why you need to go back out there so badly?
告诉我 小德瑞 为什么
为什么你一定要再回到台上
Because I'm still scared.
因为我还是很害怕
No matter what happens tonight
when I leave...
不论发生什么事
今晚 当我离开的时候
...I don't want to be scared anymore.
我不想再害怕了
...Due to his injury, Dre Parker
cannot return to the ring...
那么由于受伤的原因
德瑞・帕克没有办法
再次回到我们的比赛现场了
Wait, Dre Parker will fight!
等一等 德瑞・帕克还可以比赛
Hold on!
等等
The championship goes toK
冠军是…
Dre Parker will go on with the match.
德瑞・帕克继续比赛
Why let him go on...
怎么就让他继续比赛了
Dre Parker will go on with the match!
德瑞・帕克将会继续比赛
Come on! Shao Dre!
加油 小德瑞
Go!
开始
The red side gets one point.
红方一分
Shao Dre?
小德瑞
程1分 帕克0分
加油 德瑞 你可以的 德瑞
Come on, Dre.
You can do this, Dre.
开始
帕克1分 程1分
停
- You okay?
- Yes, I'm okay.
你还好吗
嗯 我可以
No mercy.
不能心软
Salute!
敬礼
Ready!
预备
Go!
开始
帕克2分 程2分
The score is tied.
The next point wins!
现在打成平局
再得一分就是我们今天本场的冠军
Come on!
加油
Go!
开始
The blue side gets one point.
蓝方一分
Champion of the tournament is...
这次比赛的冠军是
You won...
你赢了
Sir, please leave it to me.
老师 让我来吧
Dre! Dre!
德瑞 德瑞
I'm so proud of you.
我真为你而骄傲
Master!
师傅